iadt.ie 2019-12-07

# Privacy + Cookies | IADT

## Online Services and Website Privacy Policy

Dun Laoghaire Institute of Art Design and Technology (“Institute”) recognises the importance of protecting personal privacy. This privacy statement outlines how the Dun Laoghaire Institute of Art Design and Technology collects, uses and protects information about you when you access any Institute website or when you sign up to our services, mobile applications, regular newsletters, enter competitions, complete web-surveys, order products or take up an offer we may ask for personal information about you. This can include information such as your name, e-mail address, postal address, telephone or mobile number or date of birth. Different services may ask for different types of information.

If you are aged 16 or under, you must get your parent/guardian’s permission before you provide us with your personal information. Unless you have this consent you are not allowed to give us your information.

Whenever personal data is collected via your use of these Institute websites or online services, that information will only be used in accordance with this privacy policy and relevant legislation.

The Institute may revise this privacy statement from time to time. Changes to this privacy statement will be posted here so you should periodically check this policy to review the most recent statement.

## The information we collect and how it is used

We may ask you to provide personal information to enable us to provide a specific service that you have requested, for example requesting an Institute prospectus, or we may ask you to voluntarily complete an online survey. The web page requesting this personal information will provide details of how the information will be used. All personal data collected in this way will be processed in accordance with the Data Protection Act and the EU’s General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) and will only be used for the purpose(s) specified at the time of collection.

## Web log files

In common with most websites we automatically log certain information about every visit to the site. This includes your IP address* and information relating to your requests from our servers, for example date and time, referrer, user agent (browser), request type and details of request size. This information is anonymous unless you have logged in to a secure area of the site using an identifying username and password. The information is used to help us manage the website (e.g. detecting bugs, broken links) and where necessary to investigate potential computer misuse or breaches in Institute regulations. Under normal circumstances these log files will only be accessed by authorised members of Institute staff under security controls, however we do have a legal obligation to make our log files available to external authorities such as the An Garda Siochana, when requested.

## Information about the device you are using

If you download one of our apps, such as the Blackboard, we may collect information about the device you use to access the app, including, where available, the device’s unique identifiers, operating system, browser type and mobile network information as well as the device’s telephone number, for system administration and to report statistical information. We may also collect information about your use of the app such as what pages you look at and what elements you tap or pages you interact with so we can improve your experience with our apps into the future.

## Information about transactions

If you purchase something from us such as print credit or an replacement student ID card, we will make a record of the details of that transaction.

## Contact information

If you contact us, through email, online forms or through one of our sites we may keep a record of that correspondence.

## How we use cookies

Cookies are small text files which are placed on your computer’s hard drive to help us monitor the use of our website and provide access to certain features. A cookie does not identify the individual only the computer used, it does not gives us access to your computer.

Cookies enable us to provide you with a better experience of our website. The Institute uses cookies to track user behaviour, improve and personalise the services we offer and remember previous actions (e.g. which items have been placed in an online shopping basket). We do not use cookies which have a high impact on your privacy and will regularly review the use of cookies on our site to protect your privacy.

In common with many organisations the Institute uses ‘Google Analytics’ a web analytics service provided by Google Inc to enable us to analyse how our website is used. This means that information about use of our website may be transmitted to Google Inc. This information does not enable you to be identified and is not considered privacy intrusive. Users of the most popular web browsers can install a browser add-on which prevents information being transferred to Google, see: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

You can change the settings in your browser to refuse cookies. However in doing so you may be unable to access certain features of our website. You can also delete cookies using the tools in your browser. For more information about cookies please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

## Security and how we look after your information

The Institute is committed to ensuring the security of Institute websites, online forms, online surveys and any information you provide using those sites. The Institute has procedures in place to help protect against loss, misuse and alteration of information. Your information will be processed by staff where it is necessary to fulfil an order, process payment details or provide you with other support services.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your information, we cannot guarantee its security and when giving us your information you do so at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

Where you require a password to access a specific Institute website (or part of) you are responsible for keeping the password safe and secure at all times, you must not share it with anyone else.

We will hold your information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant service, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us. If you change your registration profile to opt-out of receiving communications from us, your record may stay on the system so we can ensure that we do not contact you in the future. If you wish to cancel your registration with any of IADT’s websites or newsletters, you may do so by contacting us using the details available in the ‘Contact Us’ section of the website or by emailing foi@iadt.ie.

The Institute website contains links to other websites which may be of interest to users. We are not responsible for the content of these websites and have no control over any information you may provide to third parties and we advise that you review the other websites’ policies before providing personal information.

The information that we collect from you may under rare or exceptional circumstances be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (this includes the EU, Iceland, Norway and Lichtenstein), however we endeavour to keep your information with-in the EEA and where possible limit the information to Ireland.

More information on security can be accessed at the [ITC Policy](https://www.iadt.ie/study/current-student-info/information-services) section of this site.

Within the Institute domain (.iadt.ie) you may find websites over which the Institute has no editorial responsibility. Such sites can include the websites of student organisations, etc. While the Institute expects compliance with this privacy statement at such sites, please contact webmaster@iadt.ie if you encounter Institute websites that are not compliant with this privacy and cookie statement.

## Your Rights

The Institute will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have informed you, have your permission or are required to by law. Information may be shared with third parties who are under contract to act for us.

The Institute takes its responsibilities under the Data Protection Act (DPA) and the EU’s General Data Protection Regulations seriously and will only process personal data in accordance with the Act. Under the DPA you have the right to access your personal data held by the Institute. Further information about this is available from the [Freedom of Information](https://www.iadt.ie/contact/freedom-of-information) section of this site.

Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to request a copy of the information we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. For information requests and will require you to prove your identity with 2 pieces of approved photographic identification. We will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you on our files. If you believe the information we are holding on you is incorrect or you require further information about how we use your information please contact foi@iadt.ie

*An IP address is a unique number or address given to every computer or device when it connects to a network allowing it to be identified and communicated with.
